Vy Nguyen

Web Developer | 619-484-8576 | vy.t.nguyen.11@gmail.com | Grand Prairie, TX

Summary

Natural problem solver and quick learner with high attention to details. Passionate about writing clean and efficient code, developing solutions, and learning new technologies. Experience with working in a fast pace environment and having strong time management skills, great communication skills, and a positive attitude.

Skills

React . React Native . React Redux . AngularJS . JavaScript . jQuery . HTML5 . CSS3
Sass . Bootstrap . Reactstrap . Flexbox . Drupal . Wordpress . PHP . Node.js . MySQL
MongoDB . Loopback . Redis . Git . Github . Command Line Interface . Photoshop
Visual Studio Code . Xcode . Jira . Bitbucket . Teamwork . Asana

Education

09/2017 - 04/2018

Origin Code Academy | San Diego, CA - Full Stack Web Developer Certification

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Express.js, React.js, Node.js, Redux, Database Theory, MongoDB, MySQL, Loopback, Redis, Command Line Interface, Git, and more

01/2008 - 05/2011

East Texas Baptist University | Marshall, TX - Bachelor of Arts in University Studies

Magna Cum Laude, 3.7 GPA
Alpha Chi Honor Society & Dean's List with Honors

Portfolio

Website: vunit.io Portfolio: vunit.io/portfolio Github: github.com/vunit2007

Code Challenges: codewars.com/users/vunit2007/completed_solutions

Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/vy-nguyen-715417102

Experience

09/2019 to 01/2020

101 Network | La Jolla, CA - Web Developer

- Utilized Wordpress, PHP, JavaScript, jQuery, HTML, & CSS.
- Developed responsive and dynamic Wordpress websites that ensured high traffic and user-friendly experience.

- Ensured cross-browser, cross-platform, and multiple device type compatibility for all web solutions.
- Supported operations team with day-to-day requests related to website functionality and performance.
- Involved in all aspects of the application development lifecycle: Idea, Development, QA,
 Documentation, Implementation, and Integration
- Developed, maintained, troubleshooted and enhanced existing web applications and services.
- Adhered to project schedules and effectively reported progress to meet challenging deadlines.
- Performed code reviews before merging into Github.

Reason for Leaving & Hiatus: Company had a major layoff and went out of business a few months later during Covid. California's strict and indefinite lockdown made it difficult to find work during the pandemic.

10/2018 to 04/2019

Tragic Media | San Diego, CA - Front-end Developer

- Took Photoshop files from design and created responsive landing pages using Angular 7, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, Sass, and Flexbox.
- Utilized Wordpress, Drupal, Filezilla, Photoshop, Git, Npm, and Gulp during the production process.
- Worked closely with other developers in researching, implementing, testing, debugging, deploying, and maintaining web applications.
- Completed tasks using teamwork.com for agile/scrum development methodology

Reason for Leaving & Hiatus: One of my projects got terminated and there was not sufficient work for me to do afterwards. Took a few months off to do independent studying before applying again.

08/2018 to 09/2018

NewRocket | Vista, CA - Software Developer Intern

- Utilized AngularJS, HTML5, CSS3, Sass, and Bootstrap.
- Helped troubleshoot widgets and service portals using the ServiceNow platform.

03/2018 to 05/2018

Ficus | San Diego, CA - Software Developer Contractor

- Designed, built, tested, and deployed Ficus Mini, the beta edition to the gamified stock-trading Ficus app (available on iOS).
- Built the Ficus Mini app using React-Native for the front-end and MongoDB, Express, Redis, and Loopback for the backend.
- Utilized Xcode, Expo, and Photoshop.
- Completed tasks using Jira and BitBucket for agile/scrum development methodology.

02/2012 to 09/2017

AXA Advisors, Scottrade, JPMorgan Chase Bank - Financial Professional

- Met with clients to discuss their short-term and long-term financial goals.
- Came up with solutions, strategies, and the right products to help clients achieve their financial objectives.